The west just got wilder.
Young Guns II is a western, adventure film directed by Geoff Murphy.
Three of the original five "young guns" — Billy the Kid, Jose Chavez y Chavez, and Doc Scurlock — return in Young Guns, Part 2, which is the
story of Billy the Kid and his race to safety in Old Mexico while being trailed by a group of government agents led by Pat Garrett.
William H. 'Billy the Kid' Bonney, played by Emilio Estevez.
Josiah Gordon 'Doc' Scurlock, played by Kiefer Sutherland.
Jose Chavez y Chavez, played by Lou Diamond Phillips.
Arkansas Dave Rudabaugh, played by Christian Slater.
Patrick Floyd 'Pat' Garrett, played by William Petersen.
Hendry William French, played by Alan Ruck.
Young Guns II is a 1990 American Western action film
and a sequel to Young Guns (1988).
It stars Emilio Estevez, Kiefer Sutherland, Lou Diamond Phillips, and
Christian Slater, and features William Petersen as Pat Garrett.
It was written by John Fusco and directed by Geoff Murphy.
It follows the life of Billy the Kid, played by Emilio Estevez, in the years following the Lincoln County War in which Billy was part of The Regulators,
a group of around six highly skilled gunmen avenging the death of John Tunstall – and the years leading up to Billy's documented death.
The film is told by Brushy Bill Roberts, a man who in 1950
appeared claiming to be the real Billy the Kid.
While the film takes some creative license, it does show some of the main events leading up to Billy's documented death, including his talks with Governor
Lew Wallace, his capture by friend-turned-foe Sheriff Pat Garrett, his trial and his subsequent escape in which he killed two deputies.
A sequel, Young Guns III, is currently in development.
The film explores themes of prison, prostitute, sheriff, bounty hunter, mexico.